Finding Aid for the Ruth St. Denis Papers LSC.1031
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4: Performance and dance materials, 1910s-1960s
  - Subseries 4.1: Choreography and performance notes, 1910s-1960s
    - Performance drawings, 1920s (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Performance notes and drawings, 1960s (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Drawings for performances, undated (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Choreography, July 1959 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Drawings by Ruth St. Denis and notes, 1960s (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - Original artwork by Ruth St. Denis and others, 1940s-1960s (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - Performance materials, 1950s (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - Performance material, 1900s-1920s (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Performance materials, 1930s (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - Performance materials, 1940s (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - Christmas pageant notes, 1957 (Box 124, Folder 11)
    - "Magnificat Notebook" no. 1, 1955 May 15 (Box 124, Folder 12)
    - Magnificat Notes, 1955 (Box 124, Folder 13)
    - "Magnificat Notebook" no. 2, 1955 (Box 124, Folder 14)
    - Performance materials, 1950s (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Performance materials, 1950s (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Performance materials, 1950s (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - Performance materials, 1960s (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Performance materials, 1960s (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Rehearsal notes, 1964 (Box 148, Folder 6)
    - Performance materials, 1960s (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Performance materials, 1960s (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Performance materials, 1960s (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Original drawnings by Ruth St. Denis and others, 1962-1965 (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - "The Woman and the Dragon, undated (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - "Dances of Burma", undated (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Taj clippings, undated (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - Notes on Ruth St. Denis's television shows, undated (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 151, Folder 2)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - Performance materials, undated (Box 151, Folder 4)
    - Handwritten notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4.2: Performance research/resources, 1910s-1960s
    Contains text and images about eastern cultures, particularly Indian culture, that S. Denis used for research when developing new dances. The majority of the materials are magazine clippings.
    - Performance research materials, undated (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Hawaiian research, undated (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous performance materials, 1925, 1940s-1960s, undated (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous designs, 1965, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Face and hand drawings, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Costume, set, and prop design drawings, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4.3: Education and dance center materials, 1940s-1960s
    Contains programs, flyers, and administrative records related to the Denishawn School and School of Divine Dance, Society of Spiritual Arts Church, Creative Arts Colony, Temple materials, Rhythmic Choir, and teaching materials St. Denis used for her classes.
    - Rhythmic choir, 1930s-1940s (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Rhythmic choir, 1950s (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Rhythmic choir, 1960s (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Ruth St. Denis and her Rhythmic choir, undated (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Rhythmic choir, undated (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Rhythmic choir notes, 1965 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Rhythmic choir, 1960s (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Rhythmic choir, undated (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Temple materials, 1920s-1930s (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Temple materials, 1930s (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Temple materials, 1930s (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Temple materials, 1940s (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Temple materials, 1940s (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Temple materials, 1942 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Temple materials, 1942-1950 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Temple materials, 1950s-1960s, undated (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Temple materials, undated (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Temple records, undated (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Creative arts colony, 1950s-1960s, undated (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Delsarte Class, 1923 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Teaching materials, 1937 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Teaching materials, 1950s (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Teaching materials, 1960s (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Teaching materials, undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Teaching materials, undated (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Teaching materials, undated (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Teaching materials, undated (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - School of Divine Dance, 1940s-1960s, undated (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - The Society of Spiritual Arts, 1940s-1960s, undated (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 4.4: Sheet music, 1920s-1960s
    Contains sheet music, some of which are annotated with dance notations.
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Music, 1940s-1950s, undated (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Sheet music, 1920s-1950s, undated (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Sheet music, 1929 (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 163)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 164)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 165)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 166)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 167)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 168)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 169)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 170)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 171)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 172)
    - Sheet music, undated (Box 173)
- Series 5: Media, 1900s-1960s
  The media series contains photographs, negatives, glass negatives, photographic printing plates, and reel-to-reel tapes. Materials span from the 1880s to 1968 and document many of St. Denis's dances and live performances, publicity photos, her travels, the Denishawn dancers, her students, and her personal life.
  Organization and Arrangement
  The majority of the materials are arranged in chronological order, expect those that are arranged in alphabetical order according to dance title.
  - Subseries 5.1: Photographs, 1900s-1960s
    Contains photographs from the 1890s to 1968 that document St. Denis's personal life, travels, dances, Denishawn dancers, publicity photos, live performances, and events.
    - Ancient Greek Suite, 1910s-1920s (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Ancient Greek Suite: Sappho, 1920s-1930s (Box 155, Folder 3)
    - Angkorr Vat Ballet, 1920s (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Ballet of Light, 1950s (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Ballet of the Zodiac, 1916 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - The Cobras, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Cuadro Flamenco, 1920s (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Cuadro Flamenco, 1920s-1930s (Box 155, Folder 4)
    - Duet Suite, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - East Indian Suite, 1930s-1940s (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Egypta, 1900s (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Egypt Ballet, 1910s (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Elizabeth the Queen, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - European Suite, 1920s (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - The Gift of Eternal Life, 1930 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Gleaning from Buddha Fields, 1930s (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Gleaning from Buddha Fields, 1940s (Box 155, Folder 2)
    - Graham, Martha, 1920s (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Greek Scene, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Gregorian Chant, 1950s-1960s (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Gregorian Chant, undated (Box 155, Folder 5)
    - He is Risen, undated (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - He Is Risen, undated (Box 155, Folder 7)
    - Humphrey, Doris, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - I Enter the Darkness, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - The Incense, 1906, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - The Incense, 1940s (Box 155, Folder 8)
    - Informal - general, 1910s-1930s (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Informal - general, 1940s-1950s (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Informal - general, 1950s-1960s (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Informal - general, 1960s (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Informal - travel, c 1910 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Informal - family, undated (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Informal - family, March 1932 (Box 155, Folder 9)
    - Informal - Weidman reception, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Ishtar of the Seven Gates, circa 1910s (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Julnar of the Sea, circa 1910s (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Jurgen, 1920s-1930s (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Krishnamurti Poem, undated (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - The Lamp, 1920s (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Legends from the Vienna Woods, undated (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Liebestraum, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Light of Asia, 1910s (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - The Madonna (Blue), 1955 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Blue Madonna, 1958 (Box 155, Folder 10)
    - The Madonna (Church), 1939 (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - The Madonna (Gold), 1950s (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - The Madonna (White), 1950s (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - Captions, undated (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Madwoman of Chaillot, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Miriam, Sister of Moses, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Mona Vana, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Musical visualization, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Music visualizations, undated (Box 155, Folder 6)
    - Nature Rhythms, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Nautch, 1906-1946 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Nautch, 1927 (Box 155, Folder 11)
    - Omika and Kwannon, 1913-1949 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Oureida, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Seed of the Lotus, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - The Peacock, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - The Prophetess, 1935-1939 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Radha, 1906 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Radha, 1941-1943 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Radha, 1900s-1920s (Box 155, Folder 12)
    - Salome, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Salome, 1950-1951 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Salome, undated (Box 155, Folder 14)
    - Sarah and Abraham, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Shawn, Ted, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Shawn, Ted, 1942-1962 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Shawn, Ted, 1900s-1920s (Box 155, Folder 13)
    - Shawn and St. Denis, 1920-1925 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Shawn and St. Denis, 1949-1956 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Siamese Ballet, 1917-1920s (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Soaring, undated (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Spirit of the Sea, undated (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Straussiana, undated (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Students with St. Denis, circa 1933 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Students - general, 1920s-1960s (Box 155, Folder 15)
    - Students - general, 1920s (Box 155, Folder 16)
    - Students (individual), 1919 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Students (individual), undated (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Students (grouped), 1934, undated (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Students - music visualizations, 1920s (Box 155, Folder 17)
    - Students - rhythmic choir, 1928 (Box 155, Folder 18)
    - Studies - Deirdre, 1910s (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Studies - East India, 1920s-1940s (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Studies - Egyptian, 1916, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Studies - Freedom and Liberty, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Studies - Grecian, 1920s-1930s (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Studies - hemet, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Studies - grand avenue, 1910s (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Studies - Jacob's Pillow, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Studies - Javanese and Chinese, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Studies - MacDowell Col., 1910s (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Studies - Madonna, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Studies - Miscellaneous, 1920s (Box 155, Folder 19)
    - Studies - Oriental, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Studies - Oriental, 1960s (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Studies - Oriental, 1940s (Box 155, Folder 20)
    - Studies - personal, 1920s (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Studies - personal, 1890s-1910s (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Studies - personal, 1920s-1930s (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Studies - personal, 1910s-1920s (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Studies - personal, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Studies - personal, circa 1950s (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Studies - personal, 1960s (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Studies - personal, 1960s (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Studies - personal, 1940s-1960s (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Studies - personal, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Studies - personal, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Studies - personal, 1950s (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Studies - personal, 1920s-1930s (Box 155, Folder 21)
    - Studies - Siamese, 1918-1922 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Studies - Spanish, 1920s (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Studies - The Sunken Cathedral, 1935 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Tangore poem, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Theodora, 1918 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Theodora, undated (Box 155, Folder 22)
    - Visions of the Aissoua, 1920s (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Wheeler, Pearl, 1900s (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - White Jade and Quan Yin, 1940s-1950s (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - White Jade and Quan Yin, 1950s (Box 155, Folder 23)
    - Xochitl, circa 1920s (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - The Yogi, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - The Yogi, 1940s (Box 155, Folder 1)
    - Studies - Yosemite, 1910s (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified dances, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Photographs of paintings, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Photographs: Early life, 1900s-1930s (Box 138, Folder 1)
      Includes personal and dance performance photographs.
    - Photographs: Early life, 1900s-1930s (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - Photographs: Early life, 1900s-1930s (Box 138, Folder 3)
      Includes St. Denis in costume, performance photographs, and students in costume.
    - Photographs: Early life, 1900s-1930s (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - Photograph album: Early life, 1900s-1930s (Box 138, Folder 5)
      Includes personal photographs and outdoor dance photographs.
    - Photographs, 1900s-1940s (Box 139, Folder 1)
      Includes costume and performance photographs, photographs with Ted Shawn.
    - Photographs, 1914-1937 (Box 139, Folder 2)
      Includes "Arabian Suite" proof sheet in costume with Ted Shawn and St. Denis portraits.
    - Photographs, 1900s-1940s (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Photographs, 1900s-1940s (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, 1939-1949 (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, 1945-1949 (Box 139, Folder 6)
      Includes St. Denis having makeup applied and in costume.
    - Photographs, 1940s (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - Photographs, 1940s (Box 139, Folder 8)
      Includes portraits of St. Denis in costume
    - Scrapbook, 1940s-1951 (Box 139, Folder 9)
      Includes outdoor dance photographs, personal and dance performance photographs.
    - Photographs, 1900s-1940s (Box 140, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs of students, Ted Shawn, photographs given to St. Denis from friends, and performance photographs.
    - Scrapbook, 1910s (Box 140, Folder 2)
      Includes nature photographs and outdoor dance photographs.
    - Photographs, 1900s-1940s (Box 140, Folder 3)
      Includes dance performance photographs, photographs given to Ted Shawn from friends, and personal photographs in Spain.
    - Photographs, 1900s-1940s (Box 140, Folder 4)
      Includes personal photographs, dance performance photographs of Ruth St. Denis, Ted Shawn, and students, and signed photographs given to St. Denis and Shawn.
    - Photographs (1 of 2), 1950s (Box 141, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs of St. Denis outdoors in Hemet, California; St. Denis in costume; and St. Denis with other dancers and casts.
    - Photographs (2 of 2), 1950s (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Photographs, 1950s (Box 141, Folder 3)
      Includes personal photographs, St. Denis in a pilates studio, photographs from friends, performance photographs, and misc. photographs.
    - Photographs of St. Denis, 1950s (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, 1950s-1960s (Box 141, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of St. Denis, dance performance photographs, and outdoor photographs.
    - Photographs, 1950s (Box 141, Folder 6)
      Includes personal and dance photographs of St. Denis.
    - Photographs, 1950s (Box 141, Folder 7)
      Includes photographs of students and St. Denis.
    - Photographs, 1960s (Box 142, Folder 1)
      Includes personal photographs of St. Denis and performance photographs.
    - Photographs, 1960s (Box 142, Folder 2)
      Includes St. Denis as "White Madonna," St. Denis with friends, portraits, and photographs in Hemet, California.
    - Photographs, 1960s (Box 142, Folder 3)
      Includes photographs of St. Denis and misc. photographs.
    - Photographs, 1960s (Box 142, Folder 4)
      Miscellaneous photographs
    - Photographs, 1960s (Box 142, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of St. Denis and at her studio and performance photographs.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 143, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of St. Denis, Denishawn Dancers, and misc. photographs.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 143, Folder 4)
      Includes portraits of St. Denis and misc. photographs.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 143, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of performances including "Antigone" and students.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 143, Folder 6)
      Includes student, performances, and personal photographs.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 144, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of dancers and performances.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 144, Folder 5)
      Includes photographs of St. Denis and performances
    - Photographs, undated (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 144, Folder 7)
      Includes photographs of dancers and miscellaneous photos.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 145, Folder 1)
      Includes personal photos of St. Denis.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 145, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of St. Denis
    - Photographs, undated (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 145, Folder 4)
      Includes personal photos and photos of St. Denis.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 146, Folder 1)
      Inlcudes personal and dance photographs of St. Denis.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 146, Folder 4)
      Primarily photographs of St. Denis.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 146, Folder 6)
      Includes photographs of St. Denis.
    - Photographs, undated (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Photographs: Album pages, undated (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Photographs: Album pages, undated (Box 147, Folder 3)
    - Photographs, 1900s-1960s (Box 154)
  - Subseries 5.2: Negatives, 1900s-1960s
    Includes glass negatives that depict portraits and performances.
    - Photographic plates, undated (Box 181, Box 180)
    - Negatives, undated (Box 153, Folder 11)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Seven envelopes of negatives unvailable due to damaged condition.
    - Negatives of Denishawn house New York, St. Paul, Pine Oaks, Yosemite, undated (Box 176, Folder 1)
    - Negatives, miscellaneous, undated (Box 176, Folder 2)
    - Negatives, Salome Balinese films, Synchoric films - stadium children, Yosemite, dance, 1931, undated (Box 176, Folder 3)
    - Negatives, performances, undated (Box 176, Folder 4)
    - Negatives, peroformances, St. Denis, undated (Box 176, Folder 5)
    - Negatives, performances, undated (Box 176, Folder 6)
    - Negatives, performances, dancers, undated (Box 176, Folder 7)
    - Negatives, performances, dancers, undated (Box 176, Folder 8)
    - Negatives, miscellaneous, undated (Box 176, Folder 9)
    - Negatives, dancers, performances, undated (Box 176, Folder 10)
    - Negatives, dancers, undated (Box 176, Folder 11)
    - Negatives, performances, dancers, undated (Box 176, Folder 12)
    - Glass negatives
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Ahasuerus," San Diego, Balboa Park, undated (Box 177, Folder 1)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Ahasuerus," San Diego, Balboa Park, undated (Box 177, Folder 2)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, Buddhist monk, undated (Box 177, Folder 3)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo at studio, undated (Box 177, Folder 4)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, buddhist monk, undated (Box 177, Folder 5)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, buddhist monk, undated (Box 177, Folder 6)
      - Ruth St. Denis - with pet dog -"Chief" in pose "affection", slide is missing a part (DAMAGED), undated (Box 182)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo "Cobra", undated (Box 177, Folder 8)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo "Cobra", undated (Box 177, Folder 9)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo "Cobra", undated (Box 177, Folder 10)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo "Cobra", undated (Box 177, Folder 11)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Cuadio Flamenco", undated (Box 177, Folder 12)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Cuadio Flamenco", undated (Box 177, Folder 13)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Cuadio Flamenco", undated (Box 177, Folder 14)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Cuadio Flamenco", undated (Box 177, Folder 15)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Cuadio Flamenco", undated (Box 177, Folder 16)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Cuadio Flamenco", undated (Box 177, Folder 17)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Cuadio Flamenco", undated (Box 177, Folder 18)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Cuadio Flamenco", undated (Box 177, Folder 19)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Cuadio Flamenco", undated (Box 177, Folder 20)
      - Ruth St. Denis - draped figure, undated (Box 177, Folder 21)
      - Ruth St. Denis - head study, East Indian Nautch, undated (Box 177, Folder 22)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian nautch, "Street Nautch", undated (Box 177, Folder 23)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian nautch, "Street Nautch", undated (Box 177, Folder 24)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian nautch, "Street Nautch", undated (Box 177, Folder 25)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian nautch, undated (Box 177, Folder 26)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian nautch, undated (Box 177, Folder 27)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian, undated (Box 177, Folder 28)
      - Ruth St. Denis - 3 negatives, East Indian study, undated (Box 177, Folder 29)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian nautch, undated (Box 177, Folder 30)
      - Ruth St. Denis - in East-Indian Sari - New York, undated (Box 177, Folder 31)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian study, undated (Box 177, Folder 32)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian study, undated (Box 177, Folder 33)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, East Indian study, undated (Box 177, Folder 34)
      - Ruth St. Denis - in Egyptian Hall, "Egyptian", undated (Box 177, Folder 35)
      - Ruth St. Denis - study, Egyptian, undated (Box 177, Folder 36)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo - "Gold Waltz," 5 negatives, undated (Box 177, Folder 37)
      - Ruth St. Denis - study, in "Incense" costume, undated (Box 177, Folder 38)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Incense," at studio 160 E-48th St. - NY, undated (Box 177, Folder 39)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Incense," photo taken at studio 160 E-48th St. - NY, undated (Box 177, Folder 40)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Incense", undated (Box 177, Folder 41)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, studio photo in "Incense" costume, undated (Box 177, Folder 42)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 43)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 44)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 45)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 46)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 47)
      - Ruth St. Denis - solo, "Kwan Yin", undated (Box 177, Folder 48)